A Guide to the Department of Confederate Military Records, 1859-1996
Library of Virginia
- Series III: Miscellaneous Records
  - John Brown's Raid Unit Records
    - Cavalry
      - 2nd Regiment (Ashby's Co.) (Mountain Rangers) (See Also Oversized - Drawer 1), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 6)
      - 3rd Regiment (Drake's Co.) (See Also Oversized - Drawer 1), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 7)
      - Carter's Co. (Loudoun Light Horse) (See Also Oversized - Drawer 1), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 8)
      - Rinehart's Co. (Shepherdstown Cav.) (See Oversized - Drawer 1), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 9)
      - Scott's Co. (Black Horse Troop) (See Also Oversized - Drawer 1), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - Infantry
      - 1st Regiment
        - Co. A (Elliott's Co.) (See Oversized - Drawer 2), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 11)
        - Co. C (Moore's Co.) (See Oversized - Drawer 2), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 12)
        - Co. E (Richmond Light Inf. Blues) (Patton's Co.) (See Oversized - Drawer 2), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 13)
        - Co. F (Cary's Co.), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 14)
      - 3rd Regiment
        - Williams' Co. (Montpelier Guards) (See Also Oversized - Drawer 2), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 15)
      - 23rd Regiment
        - Clopton's Co. (Rocky Ridge Rifles) (See Oversized - Drawer 2), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 16)
      - 31st Regiment
        - Clarke's Co. (Clarke's Riflemen), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 17)
        - Funk's Co. (Marion Riflemen) (See Oversized - Drawer 2), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 18)
        - Haines' Co. (Continental Morgan Guards), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 19)
        - Reed's Co. (No. 2), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 20)
        - Smith's Co. (No. 8) (See Oversized - Drawer 2), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 21)
      - 44th Regiment
        - Adams' Co. (Mounted Riflemen) (See Oversized - Drawer 2), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 22)
      - 48th Regiment
        - Anthony's Co. (Fincastle Rifles) (See Also Oversized - Drawer 2), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 23)
      - 55th Regiment
        - Butler's Co. (Hamtramck Guard), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 24)
        - Rowan's Co. (Jefferson Guards) (See Oversized - Drawer 2), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 25)
      - 56th Regiment
        - Everhart's Co., 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 26)
        - Jones' Co., 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 27)
        - Water's Co., 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 28)
        - White's Co. (Hillsboro Border Guard), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 29)
      - 57th Regiment
        - Shreeve's Co. (Loudoun Cavalry), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 30)
        - Tabb's Co. (Loudoun Guard), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 31)
        - Miscellaneous, 1859 (Box 46, Folder 32)
      - 67th Regiment
        - Blondel's Brass Band, 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 33)
        - Mounted Scout (See Oversized - Drawer 2), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 34)
      - 77th Regiment
        - Sheetz's Co. (See Oversized - Drawer 2), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 35)
      - 85th Regiment
        - Scrugg's Detachment (See Oversized - Drawer 2), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 36)
      - 89th Regiment
        - Alderton's Co., 1859 (Box 46, Folder 37)
        - Caldwell's Co., 1859 (Box 46, Folder 38)
        - Courtney's Co., 1859 (Box 46, Folder 39)
        - Dawson's Co., 1859 (Box 46, Folder 40)
        - Havernall's Co. (See Oversized - Drawer 2), 1859 (Box 46, Folder 41)
        - Henry's Co. (See Oversized - Drawer 2), 1859 (Box 46, Folder 42)
        - Hunter's Co., 1859 (Box 46, Folder 43)
        - Kern's Co. (See Oversized - Drawer 2), 1859 (Box 46, Folder 44)
        - Parks' Co., 1859 (Box 46, Folder 45)
        - Rider's Co., 1859 (Box 46, Folder 46)
        - Yost's Co. (Bath Guards), 1859 (Box 46, Folder 47)
        - Miscellaneous, 1859 (Box 46, Folder 48)
      - 114th Regiment
        - Cooper's Co. (See Also Oversized - Drawer 2), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 49)
      - 175th Regiment
        - Marye's Co. (Alexandria Riflemen), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 50)
        - Smith's Co. (Mt. Vernon Guards), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 51)
        - Miscellaneous (See Oversized - Drawer 2), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 52)
      - 179th Regiment
        - Co. B (Rady's Co.) (See Oversized - Drawer 2), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 53)
      - Cadet Corps, 1911 (Box 46, Folder 54)
    - Independent Companies
      - Avis' Co., 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 55)
      - Baylor's Co. (West Augusta Guard) (See Also Oversized - Drawer 3), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 56)
      - Bowen's Co. (Clarke Guards) (See Oversized - Drawer 3), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 57)
      - Bushong's Co. (Mountain Guard) (See Also Oversized - Drawer 3), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 58)
      - Clarke's Co. (Winchester Rifles) (See Oversized - Drawer 3), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 59)
      - Deans' Co. (National Grays) (See Also Oversized - Drawer 3), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 60)
      - Erwin's Co. (See Also Oversized - Drawer 3), 1859 (Box 46, Folder 61)
      - Gibbons' Co. (Harrisonburg Valley Guards) (See Also Oversized - Drawer 3), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 62)
      - Gilkerson's Co. (Bunker Hill Riflemen) (See Also Oversized - Drawer 3), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 63)
      - Hunter's Co. (Hunter's Execution Guard) (See Also Oversized - Drawer 3), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 64)
      - Johnson's Co. (Hampshire Mounted Scouts) (See Also Oversized - Drawer 3), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 65)
      - Kent's Co. (Wythe Grays) (See Oversized - Drawer 3), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 66)
      - Koonce's Co. (Harper's Ferry Guard), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 67)
      - Lamb's Co. (Woodis Riflemen) (See Also Oversized - Drawer 3), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 68)
      - Lovings' Co. (Virginia Fencibles) (See Also Oversized - Drawer 3), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 69)
      - Mallory's Co. (Monticello Guard) (See Also Oversized - Drawer 3), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 70)
      - May's Co. (Petersburg City Guard) (See Oversized - Drawer 3), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 71)
      - Miller's Co. (German Rifles) (See Oversized - Drawer 3), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 72)
      - Nadenbousch's Co. (Berkeley Border Guard) (See Also Oversized - Drawer 3), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 73)
      - Plankey's Co. (Wheeling Riflemen) (See Also Oversized - Drawer 3), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 74)
      - Scott's Co. (Petersburg Grays) (See Oversized - Drawer 3), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 75)
      - Sever's Co. (Washington Guards) (See Also Oversized - Drawer 3), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 76)
      - Sherrard's Co. (Old Dominion Grays) (See Also Oversized - Drawer 3), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 77)
      - Welch's Co. (Richardson Guards) (See Also Oversized - Drawer 3), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 78)
      - Miscellaneous (See Also Oversized - Drawer 3), 1859-1860 (Box 46, Folder 79)
  - Lists of CSA Soldiers Who Died in Union Prisons
    - Alton Confederate Cemetery (Il), 1915 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Camp Butler (Il), 1915 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Camp Douglas (Chicago, Il), 1915 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Camp Morton (Indianapolis, IN), 1915 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Camp Nelson (KY), 1915 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Camp Randall (Madison, WI), 1915 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Cave Hill Cemetery (Louisville, KY), 1915 (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Cypress Hills National Cemetery (Brooklyn, NY), 1915 (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Danville Cemetery (KY), 1915 (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - Finn's Point (N.J.) (from Fort Delaware), 1915 (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - Harrisburg, PA (City Cemetery), 1915 (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - Jefferson Barracks National Cemetery, 1915 (Box 47, Folder 12)
    - Johnson's Island (Sandusky, OH), 1915 (Box 47, Folder 13)
    - Kentucky (Harrodsburg & Lexington), 1915 (Box 47, Folder 14)
    - Loudon Park Cemetery (MD), 1915 (Box 47, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous, 1907-1915 (Box 47, Folder 16)
    - Mound City National Cemetery (Il), 1915 (Box 47, Folder 17)
    - Mount Olivet Cemetery (Frederick, MD), 1915 (Box 47, Folder 18)
    - Philadelphia National Cemetery, 1915 (Box 47, Folder 19)
    - Point Lookout (MD), 1915 (Box 47, Folder 20)
    - Rock Island (Il), 1915 (Box 47, Folder 21)
    - Washington, D.C. (Congressional Cemetery), 1915 (Box 47, Folder 22)
    - Woodlawn National Cemetery (Elmira, NY), 1907-1915 (Box 47, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous (Folders)
    - Act to Create the Governor & Manager of the Exchequer of the Confederate States of America, 1865 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Acts Related to the Preservation of Confederate Records in Virginia, 1908-1912 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Addresses, 1888-1908 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Article from "Jeffersonian" re. Sherman's March to the Sea, 1915 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Bail Bonds of Jefferson Davis (duplicates) (See Oversized - Box 8), 1867 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Chicago Board of Trade Battery, 1908 (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Clippings
      - Confederate Reunion, 1908 (Box 48, Folder 7)
      - Raids Around Richmond, 1864 (Box 48, Folder 8)
      - Third Battalion Infantry, Co. F (Local Defense), n.d. (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - Circular, ca. 1904 (Box 48, Folder 10)
    - Commission & Official Bond of T.H. Southall for Assistant Commissary, 1864 (Box 48, Folder 11)
    - Comparative Losses, Union & Confederate, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence
      - Finance Committee, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 13)
      - Hall, Wilmer L., 1945 (Box 48, Folder 14)
      - Morgan, George H. to Joseph R. Haw (Photostats), 1866 (Box 48, Folder 15)
      - Officer from Ewell's Corps to Miss Preston (transcription), 1863 (Box 48, Folder 16)
      - Pierpont, F.H., 1861 (Box 48, Folder 17)
    - Draft of the Secretary of Virginia Military Records' Report to the Governor, 1909 (Box 48, Folder 18)
    - Form of List or Return by John R. Richardson, 1865 (Box 48, Folder 19)
    - General Robert E. Lee's Commands & List of Total Virginia Military Organizations Mentioned in War Records, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 20)
    - "John Brown's Peregrinations in Virginia Before His Raid on Harpers Ferry", 1887-1888 (Box 48, Folder 21)
    - Leave of Absence for J. Haw (photostat), 1864 (Box 48, Folder 22)
    - Lee Camp Soldier's Home Roster & Bylaws, 1910-1913 (Box 48, Folder 23)
    - Lists
      - Artillery Units, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 24)
      - Cavalry Units, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 25)
      - Companies Furnished by the Different Counties & Cities in the State, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 26)
      - Companies Furnished by the Different Counties & Cities in the State, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 27)
      - Confederate Records in Possession of the Adjutant General of Virginia, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 27)
      - Confederate Veterans at Gettysburg Encampment, 1913 (Box 48, Folder 28)
      - Infantry Units (folder 1), n.d. (Box 48, Folder 29)
      - Infantry Units (folder 2), n.d. (Box 48, Folder 30)
      - Military Pensioners from Each County (totals), n.d. (Box 48, Folder 31)
      - Militia Units, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 32)
      - Miscellaneous Papers in File Case A & B, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 33)
      - Miscellaneous Units, 1908-1909 (Box 48, Folder 34)
      - Original Muster Rolls and Other Documents Concerning the Virginia Line Compiled by Maj. Robert W. Hunter, n.d. (Box 48a, Folder 1)
      - Papers Not Catalogued, 1905 (Box 48a, Folder 2)
      - Soldiers from Various Commands, n.d. (Box 48a, Folder 3)
      - Veterans Admitted to the Lee Camp Soldiers' Home, 1915 (Box 48a, Folder 4)
    - Membership Certificates to the Pickett-Buchanan Camp, 1892-1895 (Box 48a, Folder 5)
    - Memo from the U.S. War Dept. to the Adjutant General of Virginia, 1896 (Box 48a, Folder 6)
    - Memorandum Book Containing Preliminary Notes on Local Designations of Virginia Units, n.d. (Box 48a, Folder 7)
    - Notes on Confederate Soldiers, 1906-1919 (Box 48a, Folder 8)
    - Number of Muster Rolls Turned Over to the State Librarian by the Secretary of Virginia Military Records, 1906 (Box 48a, Folder 9)
    - Poem, n.d. (Box 48a, Folder 10)
    - Printed Material, 1884-1918 (Box 48a, Folder 11)
    - Programme, n.d. (Box 48a, Folder 12)
    - Roll of the Southern Legion of Honor for the Natural Bridge District of Rockbridge Co., 1885 (Box 48a, Folder 13)
    - Tabulations of Living Veterans by County, 1911 (Box 48a, Folder 14)
    - Travel Pass from Provost Marshall's Office, 1864 (Box 48a, Folder 15)
    - Virginia Soldiers Mentioned in Special Orders, n.d. (Box 48a, Folder 16)
    - Voucher to Capt. Clifton H. Smith, 1861 (Box 48a, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous (Volumes)
    - Artillery Data Compiled by Maj. R.W. Hunter, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Catalog of Muster Rolls & Other Documents of Confederate Soldiers of Virginia Compiled by Maj. Robert W. Hunter, 1905 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Cavalry Data Compiled by Maj. R.W. Hunter, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Compiled Muster Rolls of Confederate Soldiers from Essex Co., 1911
    - Copy of Muster Roll of the First Regiment Infantry, Virginia Volunteers (2 volumes), 1901, 1920
    - Guide to Battlefields of Virginia & West Virginia, 1910
    - Index to Muster Roll Forms Distributed by the Adjutant General under Act of Assembly, 1884 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Infantry Data Compiled by Maj. R.W. Hunter, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - List of Additional Names Not Found on Original Rosters, but Carried on Pension Lists, U.S. War Dept. Material, etc., n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - List of Local Designations for CSA Infantry, Cavalry, & Artillery Units from Virginia by Regiment and County, ca. 1906 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - List of Local Designations for CSA Infantry & Cavalry Units from Virginia by Regiment, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - List of Virginia Soldiers who Applied for Pensions, but whose Records were not Found, 1913-1917 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Register of Chaplains in Virginia Units, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Register of Confederate Units & Officers Complied by Maj. Robert W. Hunter, 1904 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Register of General Officers in the CSA Army Appointed from Virginia, ca. 1910-1911 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Register of Officers & Enlisted Men from Virginia in the CSA Commissary Dept., n.d. (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Register of Officers & Enlisted Men from Virginia in the CSA Ordnance Dept., n.d. (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Register of Officers & Enlisted Men from Virginia in the CSA Quartermaster's Dept., n.d. (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Roster of Ex-Confederate Soldiers & Sailors, Vol. I and II, 1900
    - Secretary of Virginia Military Records Index to Incoming Correspondence, 1904-1910
    - Secretary of Virginia Military Records Letter Book, 1904-1909
    - Secretary of Virginia Military Records Office Expense Account Book, 1905-1910 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Supplementary List of Virginia Soldiers in Detached Units, Militia Companies, Local Defense Units, & Miscellaneous Organizations, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Scrapbooks
    - A.P. Hill Camp's Visit to Springfield, Mass. (original and photocopy), 1910 (Box 52, Folder 1-2)
    - Articles from Maj. Robert W. Hunter's "Our Confederate Column" in the Richmond Times-Dispatch (original and photocopy), 1904-1905, 1907-1909 (Box 52, Folder 3-6)
    - Clippings, 1884-1922 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Company Rosters for Soldiers Mustered into CSA Service from Richmond City & Henrico County and Published in the Richmond Dispatch, 1906 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Obituaries of Confederate Veterans (Index, Volume I and II) (original and photocopy), 1910-1914, 1914-1916 (Box 53, Folder 2-6)
  - Transcripts of General & Special Orders from the Adjutant & Inspector General's Office
    - General Orders, 1862-1864 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Special Orders
      - No. 1-50, 1862-1865 (Box 54, Folder 2)
      - No. 51-100, 1862-1865 (Box 54, Folder 3)
      - No. 101-150, 1861-1865 (Box 54, Folder 4)
      - No. 151-200, 1861-1865 (Box 54, Folder 5)
      - No. 201-250, 1862-1865 (Box 54, Folder 6)
      - No. 251-289, 1861-1865 (Box 54, Folder 7)
      - No. 290-313, 1861-1865 (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous, 1862-1865 (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - Unit Lists
    - Catalog of Muster Rolls from Commonwealth vs. J.C. Wrenn, 1910 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Infantry Battalions, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Local Defense, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Militia, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Payrolls of Tidewater Unites from Virginia and North Carolina, 1862 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Stonewall Brigade, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Unassigned Companies, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - Veteran Lists by County
    - Accomack County, 1911-1922 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Alleghany County, ca. 1900-1902 (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Augusta County, 1913 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Bedford County, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Brunswick County, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - Essex County, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - Floyd County, 1910 (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - Gloucester County, 1916 (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - Goochland County, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - Greenbrier County, 1906 (Box 56, Folder 10)
    - Greene County, 1921 (Box 56, Folder 11)
    - Hanover County, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 12)
    - Hardy County, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 13)
    - Isle of Wight County, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 14)
    - King William County, 1918 (Box 56, Folder 15)
    - Loudoun County, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 16)
    - Lunenburg County, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 17)
    - Madison County, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 18)
    - Mecklenburg County, 1906 (Box 56, Folder 19)
    - Nansemond County, 1920 (Box 56, Folder 20)
    - Pendleton County, 1910 (Box 56, Folder 21)
    - Rockingham County, 1918 (Box 56, Folder 22)
    - Shenandoah County, 1909 (Box 56, Folder 23)
    - Sussex County, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 24)
    - Warren County, 1907 (Box 56, Folder 25)
    - Washington County, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 26)
    - Lunenburg City, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 27)
    - Portsmouth City, 1904 (Box 56, Folder 28)
    - Missouri (Kansas City), 1913 (Box 56, Folder 29)
    - Oklahoma, 1912 (Box 56, Folder 30)
  - Oversized Volumes
    - Copy of Muster Roll of the First Regiment Infantry, Virginia Volunteers, 1901, 1920 (Box 57)
    - Guide to Battlefields of Virginia & West Virginia, 1910 (Box 58)
    - Roster of Ex-Confederate Soldiers & Sailors (Vol. I and II), 1900
    - Secretary of Virginia Military Records Index to Incoming Correspondence, 1904-1910 (Box 59)
    - Secretary of Virginia Military Records Letter Book, 1904-1909 (Box 59)
    - Compiled Muster Rolls of Confederate Soldiers from Essex Co., 1911 (Box 60)
  - Pardons
    - F, 1865-1866 (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - G, 1865-1866 (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - P, 1865-1866 (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - R, 1865-1866 (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Oversized Pictorial Material
    - A.P. Hill Monument (Richmond, Va.), n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Arlington Cemetery (Washington, D.C.) Confederate War Memorial (Front View, Rear View, Postcard, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 2-4)
    - Confederate Soldiers & Sailors Monument (Libby Hill Park - Richmond, Va.), n.d. (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - Confederate Veterans Reunion, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - Hollywood Cemetery (Richmond, Va.)
      - Confederate Memorial, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 7)
      - Jefferson Davis Monument (Angel, Jefferson Davis, Overall View), n.d. (Box 62, Folder 8-10)
    - Otey Battery Monument, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 11)
    - Portraits
      - Hunter, Robert W., 1904 (Box 62, Folder 12)
      - Hutton, Eppa (Brig. Gen.), 1906 (Box 62, Folder 13)
      - Lamb, John, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 14)
      - Stewart, William H. (Lt. Col.), 1907 (Box 62, Folder 15)
    - Robert E. Lee Equestrian Monument (Richmond, Va.), n.d. (Box 62, Folder 16)
    - William Carter Wickham Monument (Monroe Park - Richmond, Va.), n.d. (Box 62, Folder 17)
- Series IV: Confederate Rosters, 1861-1865
  Consists of 40 volumes (20 original and 20 photostat) compiled by the Secretary of Virginia Military Records documenting Virginia soldiers who fought for the Confederacy during the Civil War. The volumes contain an unofficial roster of soldiers from Virginia who served in the Confederate States of America during the Civil War. The rosters are organized by regiment and the soldiers are listed alphabetically according to rank. The rosters provide the name of the soldier, rank, date of enlistment or commission, and sometimes remarks including killed in battle, captured, etc. Please note that individual entries give minimal to no personal or military service. See the National Archives Compiled Service Records for more detailed service record information.
  - Infantry Regiments
    - Volume 1 (1st-11th)
    - Volume 2 (12th-22nd)
    - Volume 3 (23rd-33rd)
    - Volume 4 (34th-43rd)
    - Volume 5 (44th-52nd)
    - Volume 6 (53rd-61st)
    - Volume 7 (62nd-64th)
  - Cavalry Regiments
    - Volume 8 (1st-5th)
    - Volume 9 (6th-10th)
    - Volume 10 (11th-16th)
    - Volume 11 (17th-22nd)
    - Volume 12 (22nd-27th)
  - Volume 13 (Cavalry Battalions)
  - Infantry Battalions
    - Volume 14 (1st-27th)
    - Volume 15 (30th-46th)
  - Volume 16 (Battalion Reserves)
  - Volume 17 (Local Defense)
  - Volume 18 (Artillery Regiments, 1st-4th)
  - Volume 19 (Independent Batteries)
  - Volume 20 (Militia, Miscellaneous Units, John Brown's Raid Units, etc.)